MD. ABU SAYED

Address: House: 27, Road: 12, Nikunja-2, Dhaka-1229.

Mobile No: +8801710403867 E-mail: abusayed.wd@gmail.com

BIOGRAPHY:



Detailed-oriented, flexible, and self-motivated professional with 4.5+ years of experience in Front-End and UI development. Create reusable, well documented, lightweight, saleable web Component using HTML, CSS, SCSS, JavaScript, ES6, ReactJS, Angular, NPM, BEM technology, Atomic design. Using the also Version Control System Git. Project management tool Jira, Trello with the Agile methodology Scrum master.

EXPERIENCE:

Brain Station 23 Ltd | Dec 2018-Continuing

UI ENGINEER | Brainstation-23.com

• Build responsive, pixel-perfect, cross-browser compatible websites from PSD, AI, PDF or any other documents. • Modify the existing code as needed. • Create custom jQuery plugins and modify existing plugins. • Develop web applications using Angular update and JavaScript. • Any Project as Client Requirements.

➤ JUNIOR WEB DEVELOPER FRONTEND | Sep 2018-Nov 2018

ConstantMD | Constantmd.com

• Build responsive websites from PSD, AI or PDF • Modify existing code site. • Google-Page And Y-Slow Speed Optimize. • Any Project as Client Requirements. • Creating and customizing Wordpress theme and plugin.

➤ WEB DEVELOPER | Nov 2015-Sep 2018

Baseonesolutions | <u>Baseonesolutions.com</u>

• Build responsive, pixel-perfect, cross-browser compatible websites from PSD, AI, PDF or any other documents. • Modify the existing code as needed. • Create custom jQuery plugins and modify existing plugins. • Develop web applications using Angular 4 and jQuery. • GooglePage Speed And Y-Slow Speed Analyzing and Optimization. • Any Project As Client Requirements.

Community links:

- ❖ Stack overflow: https://stackoverflow.com/users/8477792/md-abu-sayed
- Github: https://github.com/sayed021
- LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/md-abu-sayed-b8a04010b
- Github: https://github.com/sayed021
- Jsfiddle: https://jsfiddle.net/user/sayed021/fiddles

Professional projects:

#Abbvie Pro (Adove Experience manager (AEM), ReactJs, React Storybook for UI) | abbviepro.com

Abbvie pro is an of off multi-platform web application Using the AEM **Adobe Experience Manager.** Using this application create medical, Blog site, Business share tool etc manage use it. In this application for the UI use <u>React Storybook</u> for the Build bulletproof UI components faster. Every component are unique featured, use BEM technology, maintain <u>Atomic design</u> maintain height saleable User interface with popper AEM developer guide line.

#Asset light Bangla link Web application (ReactJs, React Redux, Saga, React boilerplate) | banglalink.net

Asset light Banglalink web app is an on of Mobile operator web app. Project feature show won add Component re-usable and dynamic route (just using the order, page dynamically show only add keyword in page) dynamic page seating and set dynamic component, Bangla and English language translate. Also contain the feature are Add new connection, Friends & Family offers, blog post etc.

This application is developed using the HTML, CSS, SCSS, ReactJs, React Redox, Saga basically used the React Boilerplate.

#Rent a Car management system(React JS, SharePoint, npm)

Description: this application are use for the manage a Rent a Car system like as: (1) car booking, (2) seat Booking request, (3) request for seat and chat with Owner, (4) Add existing person in booked, (5) Seat, Car request approve or reject functionality, (6) Customer request Cancel, (7) Report by date or date range, 8) block post etc.

In this application using the SharePoint latest, ReactJS, JavaScript, SPFx, NPM packages, HTML, CSS3 etc.

Purchases Management System

Description: The application is developed using the SharePoint modern framework. It's an automated system to manage the purchases chain. Using the solution Japan Tobacco International is managing its internal process.

Used Technology: SharePoint Modern Framework, SPFX, React JS, RXJS.

Tanning Certificate:

#Web Application Development -Dot Net 3 month 2015-2016.

#National Mobile Application Development tanning and contest 5 day | ICT ministry in 2015.

#Project management methodology Agile and Scrum master | BS-23 in 2019.

Academic Qualification:

Exam Title	Subject	Institute	Result	Pas. Year	Duration
Bachelor of	CSE	Uttara	3.51	2020	4 year
Science		University	(out of 4)		
(BSc)					
Diploma in	CSE	Kishoregonj	CGPA:3.46	2015	4 year
Engineering		Polytechnic	(out of 4)		
		Institute			

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Md. Nazrul Islam Mother's Name : Sokkury Begum Date of Birth : October 10, 1994

Gender : Male

Marital Status : Unmarried Nationality : Bangladeshi

National Id No. : 19946112041000266

Religion : Islam

Current Location : Dhaka, Bangladesh

Reference:

Lutfur Rahman

Software engineer at SELISE Rockin' | selise.ch

Mobile: +8801927658173 Contact: <u>Ir@selise.ch</u>, lutfur.rahman@selise.ch

Palash Kanti Bachar

Tech Lead (SharePoint Team) at Brain Station 23

Limited.

Mobile: <u>+8801924332931</u> Email: <u>palash.kuet@gmail.com</u>